Rakesh Kumar

Sr. Interactive Developer at Sapient Global Markets

Address: L-1189, Mangol Puri, New Delhi – 110083 +91 9873 924 772 | rakeshpersonal@gmail.com | https://iamrakeshk.github.io

SUMMARY

Creative and Full-Stack Developer with **9 years** of experience doing Backend and Frontend Development adhering to best practices. Highly motivated, detail oriented, and passionate advocate of emerging frontend and backend technologies. Ability to learn new tools and concepts quickly while working independently or in a team environment and high-profile clients.

OBJECTIVE

To secure a challenging position in the corporate sector where I can apply my technical skills and experience and be a part of team that helps to achieve the organization success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SAPIENT GLOBAL MARKET

Sr. Interactive Developer (Since March 2015 to Present)

Bank of Montreal (BMO - Client Connect)

Interactive developer specialized in JavaScript, Node JS, Express, Gulp, HTML, CSS and Web Standards. Have done large scale front-end development on BMO financial website as a lead front-end developer. Taken care of all the functionalities, API calls, raw JSON transformation, optimization of API calls, performance improvements and others.

Responsibilities as a Developer:

- 1. Render application on server side with the help of Node JS and Express.
- 2. Used EJS (embedded JS) to render data on front-end.
- 3. Created functionality of Download PDF and CSV for performance data and factsheet which contains the information of funds
- 4. Implemented the High Chart with custom modification to show the performance of funds.

Skills: JavaScript, ES5, Node, Express, Nodemon, EJS, Jamine Unit Test, Iodash, JSHint, HTML/CSS, RWD, jQuery, GIT, Webstorm

Lloyds

Open banking uses 'APIs' to share information securely, without customer having to reveal his/her password. This is the same technology that tells an Uber driver who and where you are or which lets you sign in to other online accounts using Facebook.

Responsibilities as a Developer:

- 1. Developed the APIs for initiate, execute and enquiry of payment
- 2. Expose APIs to use of other part of bank
- 3. Consume APIs developed by other teams
- 4. Written the unit tests using Jasmine

Skills: JavaScript, ES6, Node, Loopback, Nodemon, Jamine Unit Test, Iodash, ESLint, GIT, Webstorm

Thesys CAT

The CAT is a Consolidated Audit Trail that tracks orders throughout their lifecycle and identifies the exchanges and broker-dealers handling them, thus allowing regulators to more efficiently and accurately track activity in eligible securities — those under the jurisdiction of the Securities and Exchange Commission (the "SEC") — throughout the U.S. markets. The CAT is created by a joint plan (CAT NMS Plan) of the Plan Participants or simply "Participants."

Responsibilities as a Developer:

- 1. Define all Tech Stacks(i.e, node, express, es6, eslint, nodemon, pm2, winston logger, lodash, jasmine, supertest) and setup project
- 2. Developed the APIs for Reporter Portal and Query Tools
- 3. Expose APIs to use of frontend developers to display data on UI
- 4. Written Unit Tests with 100% of coverage using Jasmine

Skills: JavaScript, ES6, Node, Express, Nodemon, Jamine Unit Test, Iodash, ESLint, GIT, VIM

DAMCO GROUP

Sr. Software Engineer (Since March 2013 to March 2015)

Responsibilities included front-end development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, Angular JS and Graphic Designing of Website UI, Hybrid and Native Apps. Used Bootstrap and custom CSS to make the websites responsive and browser compatible.

- 1. Develop Angular App using IONIC framework
- 2. Develop more than 10 websites used WordPress
- 3. Used JavaScript, jQuery and CSS3 to make website more interactive.
- 4. Used latest technologies and best practices and web standards.

Skills: HTML5, CSS2/3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Angular, IONIC, RWD, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, WordPress, Photoshop

18th TECHNOLOGY

Sr. Web Designer (Since January 2011 to March 2013)

Under this organization responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, handling team of 5 members, creating SEO friendly websites, theme implementation for WordPress and designing the UI and logo of websites and mobile Apps.

Skills: HTML5, CSS2/3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, RWD, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, WordPress, Photoshop, Illustrator

MAGNON SOLUTION

Assistant Manager (Since June 2010 to January 2011)

Responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, handling team, creating SEO friendly websites, theme implementation for WordPress and designing the UI and logo of websites.

Skills: HTML5, CSS2/3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Designing, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, Photoshop, Illustrator

MOSAIC ITES SERVICES

Web Designer (Since July 2008 to June 2010)

Responsibility included front-end development of website, maintaining website, creating SEO friendly websites and designing the UI and logo of websites

Skills: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Cross Browser Compatible Websites, Photoshop, Illustrator

QUALIFICATIONS

Graduation in B.A. Political Science Honors from Delhi University.

CERTIFICATIONS

ADIM(Advance Diploma in Multimedia)

2005 - 2008

Arena Multimedia - APTECH

CIC(Certificate in Computing)

2005 IGNOU

MEAN Stack and MongoDB Development Techniques

Feb, 2017

Lynda.com | License 5E519E

SKILLS

JavaScriptNode JS

• Express, Loopback

React JS

Angular JS

• Unit Testing

ReduX

MobX

• gulp, webpack

lodash

• HTML/HTML5

CSS2/3

SASS/LESS

• Responsive Web Designing

• Cross Browser/Platform Implementation

• GIT

• UI/UX Designing

Photoshop

Illustrator

PERSONAL INFO

Father's Name: Mr. Ram Iqbal Marital Status: Married Nationality: Indian

Date of Birth : 16th Sep, 1984 Language : Hindi, English